# **Raymond Chen**

250 Vale St Apt 420, Chelsea, MA 02150

**ABOUT ME** 

A recent graduate from Temple University with a degree in Computer Science, currently pursuing a master's in Software Development at Boston University. Experience in web and software development. Strong analytical and problem-solving skills. Works effectively in a team-oriented environment. Experience in designing, developing and deploying software applications. I believe that the pursuit of knowledge is a lifelong journey.

### **PROJECTS**

### TuTraffic

Technologies Used: Python, React, JavaScript

- Integrated Firebase database with React app
- Developed the frontend of a web page using React, HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Utilized OpenCV to build a machine learning model for identifying available parking spots in real-time

## OTTOMH: A Party-Thinking Game for The Web Technologies Used: Go, React, JavaScript

- Developed and implemented WebSocket communication to enhance real-time data transfer between the frontend and backend
- Designed and developed responsive web pages with React

#### Freeday Coffee Website

**Technologies Used:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, SQL, React

- Developed a dynamic data visualization platform by connecting to a database via webAPI.
- Implemented CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) functionality for a database table.

### **User Experience Project**

 Led the end-to-end design process for a food service webpage, utilizing techniques such as scoping, user research, ideation, design, validation, and iteration. (617) 716-9310 raymondcyj@outlook.com

## **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** 

Java, Python, JavaScript, C/C++, Go

Web Development:

React, Nodejs, Firebase, SQL, D3

**Design and Prototyping Tools:** 

Miro, Axure

Version Control: Git

Project Management: Agile, Jira

**Creative Tools:** 

Premiere Pro, Photoshop CC, Ilustrator CC, InDesign

## RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## Web Developer

Rinon Electronic Technology

Philadelphia, PA

Jul 2023 - Oct 2023

Designed and developed custom website for the small business and individual, meeting client requirements and deadlines.

## **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

**CSSAT** 

Sep 2022 - May 2023

Chinese Students & Scholars Association

- Coordinates events to connect students from different culture
- · Helps international students adapt to campus life

### Diamond Dogs

Sep 2022 - May 2023

- Helps animal shelters by walking, playing, and engaging with dogs
- Coordinates fundraising events to support animal adoption centers

#### EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

## **Boston University**

MS in Software Development Graduation date: Dec 2024

## Temple University, College of Science and Technology

B.S. Computer Science Graduation date: May 2023

Dean's list: Spring 2021, Spring 2023

GPA: 3.65

## **LANGUAGES**

English, Mandarin, Cantonese